<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Voip on Leif Madsen.</title>
    <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/tags/voip/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Voip on Leif Madsen.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/tags/voip/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Using a Nokia E71 with Asterisk (3G or WiFi)</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/03/19/using-a-nokia-e71-with-asterisk-3g-or-wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2010 16:28:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/03/19/using-a-nokia-e71-with-asterisk-3g-or-wifi/</guid>
      <description>There was some talk in one of the IRC chat rooms today about someone trying to get their E61i working with Asterisk. I haven&amp;rsquo;t had an issue getting that phone or my E71 phone working, but regardless he was having issues. I figured I might as well spend a little bit of time today going through my configuration, both for my own reference, and so that other people can get their Nokia&amp;rsquo;s setup with Asterisk as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New headset thanks to e4voip.com!</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/02/22/new-headset-thanks-to-e4voip.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2010 19:04:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/02/22/new-headset-thanks-to-e4voip.com/</guid>
      <description>Just got my new Plantronics headset from http://www.e4voip.com (or rather, the hardware store at http://www.8774e4voip.com/) and am extremely satisfied with the service. We had an issue with Purolator not wanting to deliver to the building and then not bothering to call me to let me know the address was incorrect. By the time I noticed and got the address corrected, they just decided to send back the package.
So after letting the guys at e4VoIP know what happened, they just drop shipped a headset via FedEx overnight and I had it by lunch the next day!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview from Wind Mobile launch</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/02/09/interview-from-wind-mobile-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 22:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/02/09/interview-from-wind-mobile-launch/</guid>
      <description>I was interviewed at the Wind Mobile launch a couple of months ago, and was interviewed by an online publication. I didn&amp;rsquo;t remember which online publication it was, so had forgotten all about it until I noticed someone had posted a link to it in the on-asterisk mailing list. Enjoy!
Wind Mobile launches with contract-free, unlimited plans
Globalive&amp;rsquo;s Wind Mobile brand is officially live in Toronto and will soon be opening its doors in Calgary and other Canadian cities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suzanne Bowen Interviews Leif Madsen, Asterisk Rockstar</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/07/30/suzanne-bowen-interviews-leif-madsen-asterisk-rockstar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 22:11:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/07/30/suzanne-bowen-interviews-leif-madsen-asterisk-rockstar/</guid>
      <description>Today I had the privilege to be interviewed by Suzanne Bowen of DIDX.
You can find the interview at http://www.didx.net/podcast/?p=episode&amp;amp;name=2009-07-30_leifmadsenjul312009.mp3
Hope you enjoy!
Here is a description of the interview:
&amp;ldquo;Truth is that I &amp;ldquo;met&amp;rdquo; the authors of the book &amp;ldquo;Asterisk, the Future of Telephony&amp;rdquo; when I was an English teacher and had volunteered over email to help edit the documentation. It was a joy to interview Leif Madsen. The Asterisk rockstar* shares with us the history of how he became interested in voice, telephony, Asterisk and open source.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
