<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</title>
    <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/categories/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 20:22:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.leifmadsen.com/categories/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Now working with CoreDial</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2012/01/04/now-working-with-coredial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 20:22:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2012/01/04/now-working-with-coredial/</guid>
      <description>As of January 3rd, I&rsquo;m now working with the CoreDial team full time. I&rsquo;ve worked with them as a consultant on their infrastructure over the last few years but now will be spending significantly more time working with the engineering team :) From the announcement, “_CoreDial is pleased to announce the addition of Leif Madsen to the CoreDial team,” said Alan Rihm, CEO at CoreDial. “Leif is a well known Asterisk consultant who specializes in distributed telephony deployments and database integration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wow, lost ticket recovery for VIA Rail is pretty much garbage</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/10/29/wow-lost-ticket-recovery-for-via-rail-is-pretty-much-garbage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2010 18:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/10/29/wow-lost-ticket-recovery-for-via-rail-is-pretty-much-garbage/</guid>
      <description>Here is the response I got from VIA Rail for a lost ticket, which was printed off at the time of departure for my return trip. Why they insist on printing the return ticket the time of departure I don&rsquo;t know, but how ridiculous is this? &ldquo;VIA Rail will not issue a free ticket against a lost or stolen ticket being reported. Customers are required to purchase a new ticket at the original fare and complete a Lost Ticket Indemnity Bond.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting article about *not* tracking holidays at Netflix</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/08/25/interesting-article-about-not-tracking-holidays-at-netflix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2010 20:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/08/25/interesting-article-about-not-tracking-holidays-at-netflix/</guid>
      <description>The following is an interesting article about not tracking workers time spent at work, or on vacation, but rather tracking their productivity. As a consultant who doesn&rsquo;t have a fixed set of hours in the day that I work, I tend to judge my productivity by the number of hours I get to bill each week (i.e. how productive was I working for customers, rather than playing Flight Simulator :)). I haven&rsquo;t tracked actual holidays for years now (since I started consulting full time out of school in 2003), and I&rsquo;m not sure I ever had a job long enough prior to school that I received any sorts of benefits of holidays.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
