<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ruby on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</title>
    <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/tags/ruby/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ruby on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/tags/ruby/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Selecting Chef Servers With Environment Variables</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2012/08/22/selecting-chef-servers-with-environment-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 18:49:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2012/08/22/selecting-chef-servers-with-environment-variables/</guid>
      <description>Today I got playing around with dynamically selecting different chef servers in preparation for migrating some of our nodes away from our chef-dev server to our chef-live server (which I&amp;rsquo;m currently in the process of building and populating with data). I had been talking in the #chef IRC channel a few weeks back about making things dynamic, or at least easily switchable, when using multiple chef servers for different groups of servers in an environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration Testing Using Jenkins (Part 1)</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2012/06/26/integration-testing-using-jenkins-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 12:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2012/06/26/integration-testing-using-jenkins-part-1/</guid>
      <description>So for the last week or so, I&amp;rsquo;ve been tasked at CoreDial with adding our own set of integration testing now that we&amp;rsquo;re moving to a more formal deployment method using chef. After much pestering of questions to thehar of Lookout Mobile Security and with help of Google, #chef and jhansche in #jenkins I&amp;rsquo;ve finally got a nice clean proof of concept that we can evaluate and likely deploy.
I&amp;rsquo;ll come back later with another article on my installation issues with jenkins and the solutions that I solved (nothing too terribly complicated), but what I wanted to blog about was the two types of tests that I&amp;rsquo;ve been focusing on and was able to finally solve.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
