<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Update on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</title>
    <link>http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/tags/update/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Update on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2011 18:26:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/tags/update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>LeifMadsen Enterprises, Inc. enters its 7th year of operation!</title>
      <link>http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/blog/2011/08/02/leifmadsen-enterprises-inc.-enters-its-7th-year-of-operation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2011 18:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/blog/2011/08/02/leifmadsen-enterprises-inc.-enters-its-7th-year-of-operation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On this day in 2005, LeifMadsen Enterprises, Inc. was formally registered as an incorporation by the government of Canada! I&amp;rsquo;ve now been consulting on Asterisk professionally for over 6 years full time (and a few years before that!). I graduated from the telecommuncations technology program at Sheridan Institute of Technology in 2004. In that time I&amp;rsquo;ve spoken at every AstriCon since 2004 (the first one), and have helped write 4 books on the subject of Asterisk (The Future of Telephony 1st, 2nd editions, The Definitive Guide 3rd edition, Cookbook). I&amp;rsquo;m quite proud of the work I have done, and the future is looking bright. The next year in business should be very exciting with some projects currently underway that will allow me to expand my business and start managing more clients with an even higher quality of service. Here&amp;rsquo;s looking forward to year seven! (And subsequently, seven is my lucky number, and the day of January on which I was born.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: Asterisk TFoT v3 Progressing Nicely</title>
      <link>http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/blog/2009/11/27/update-asterisk-tfot-v3-progressing-nicely/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2009 13:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/blog/2009/11/27/update-asterisk-tfot-v3-progressing-nicely/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jim and I have been working feverishly for the past few days, and the only thing that can cure it is more cowbell! Or probably more accurately, more writing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been making some good progress on rewriting a couple of chapters so far, and tweaking a few other ones. We&amp;rsquo;re in the process of finishing up the first drafts of the new installation chapter and the initial configuration chapter, and I&amp;rsquo;ve started work on a chapter about queues. I hope to have about 50% of the queue chapter done by the end of today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night Jim and myself went out to have a pint and to talk about the book, and we both realized how much our consulting experience is going to impact the quality of the book, and the ability to better define a set of best practices. I certainly think this edition of the book will surmount the quality of the first two editions, and the entire community will benefit from it. I&amp;rsquo;m really excited about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully we can make some good pushes over the next couple of months and get a draft of the book done early in the new year, which should set us up for a release in the spring. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how much work and time goes into creating books; the people who do this for a living are certainly a special kind of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since our plan is to more openly develop the book and get the community more actively involved in the testing and proofreading of the book, I&amp;rsquo;ll be sure to post an update here as soon as we have something available for reading.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back from Vacation!</title>
      <link>http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/blog/2009/07/15/back-from-vacation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2009 17:36:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/blog/2009/07/15/back-from-vacation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick note letting you know I&amp;rsquo;m back from vacation! Just been working on catching up on a few things, and have started working on a new article. It will be focusing on how to convert from using AgentCallbackLogin() to using the AddQueueMember() method of dynamically adding members to queues. Since AgentCallbackLogin() has been removed from Asterisk 1.6.0 and beyond, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to use the AddQueueMember() method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, all the tools we need to use it on Asterisk 1.4 are available for us, so the article will look at doing it on Asterisk 1.4 so you can get comfortable using that method before upgrading to Asterisk 1.6.0 (and beyond) if you need some of the new features. Some people have not been able to upgrade to Asterisk 1.6.0 due to the need for AgentCallbackLogin(), and have not had a chance to create the dialplans necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article will probably be called something like, &amp;ldquo;Migrating from AgentCallbackLogin() to standard dialplan methods&amp;rdquo;. I hope to have a draft out later today or tomorrow!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>