<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</title>
    <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/tags/books/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Asterisk Cookbook Is Done!</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/03/25/asterisk-cookbook-is-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 13:40:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/03/25/asterisk-cookbook-is-done/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick update that the Asterisk Cookbook is complete! We&amp;rsquo;ll be releasing it under a Creative Commons license (just like Asterisk: The Definitive Guide) again. It&amp;rsquo;ll be a 24 recipe e-book right now, with it growing over time and eventually becoming a full print edition once the size warrants it. Of course if you purchase now you help spur on additional incentive to continue making it larger. I&amp;rsquo;ve been told that you also continue to receive updates automatically as the book grows and corrections are made (which sounds pretty cool!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asterisk Cookbook Is On! (We Think :))</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/01/27/asterisk-cookbook-is-on-we-think-/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2011 14:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/01/27/asterisk-cookbook-is-on-we-think-/</guid>
      <description>After finishing the first draft of Asterisk: The Definitive Guide (3rd Edition), I&amp;rsquo;ve been a bit antsy with wanting to do some more writing. After about a week of a break (i.e. sleeping in past 7am for the first time in nearly a year), Russell Bryant and I have decided to team up on delivering the long awaited Asterisk Cookbook.
To start off with, we&amp;rsquo;ll be writing a short, 80-100 page eBook that will be distributed by O&amp;rsquo;Reilly in all the formats they support (http://oreilly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
