<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conference on Leif Madsen.</title>
    <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/tags/conference/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conference on Leif Madsen.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Leif Madsen</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2010 15:27:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/conference/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking @ IT360, April 7th, 2010</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/03/17/speaking--it360-april-7th-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2010 15:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/03/17/speaking--it360-april-7th-2010/</guid>
      <description>I will be speaking again at the IT360 conference in Toronto, ON, Canada in the Asterisk &amp;amp; Open Telephony portion of the conference. IT360 is on April 7 this year (2010) being held at the Metro Toronto Convention Centre. I will be speaking on the Super Panel – Enterprise Use, Security, Virtual Hosting, Mobility &amp;amp; More along with John Todd, Kevin Fleming, Steve Sokol, and others.
My primary focus will likely be on the large scale call centre implementations I&amp;rsquo;ve done, along with clustering, database integration, and distributed information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AstriCon 2009 Presentation -- Building a Distributed Call Center</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/11/18/astricon-2009-presentation----building-a-distributed-call-center/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 20:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/11/18/astricon-2009-presentation----building-a-distributed-call-center/</guid>
      <description>For those who missed it, you&amp;rsquo;re able to get a PDF of my AstriCon 2009 presentation from the http://www.astricon.net website.
http://images.tmcnet.com/expo/astricon/presentations/cc01-madsen-digium.pdf
There are additional presentations available from the conference as well. Check them out here: http://www.astricon.net/2009/astricon/agendaAtaGlance.aspx
Overall, the conference was extremely well attended and I had a great time. I&amp;rsquo;ve been to a lot of conferences, and AstriCon is definitely a premiere conference that is professionally run, and contains a great deal of useful information by well versed presenters with little fluff (i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
