<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Definitive Guide on Leif Madsen.</title>
    <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/tags/the-definitive-guide/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Definitive Guide on Leif Madsen.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Leif Madsen</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 17:34:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/the-definitive-guide/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Request for Reviews for Asterisk: The Definitive Guide</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/04/26/request-for-reviews-for-asterisk-the-definitive-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 17:34:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/04/26/request-for-reviews-for-asterisk-the-definitive-guide/</guid>
      <description>Recently Jim Van Meggelen, Russell Bryant and myself released the 3rd edition of the Asterisk book published by O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Media titled &amp;lsquo;Asterisk: The Definitive Guide&amp;rsquo;.
We have released this book under a Creative Commons license in the spirit of Open Source software. It is available in its entirety at http://ofps.oreilly.com/titles/9780596517342/ and for purchase through Amazon at http://www.amazon.com/Asterisk-Definitive-Guide-Leif-Madsen/dp/0596517343/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1303765969&amp;amp;sr=8-1
If you have a chance to review the book, and feel it is a useful and well written resource, we would appreciate your favorable review on Amazon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asterisk: The Definitive Guide, First Draft Complete!</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/01/12/asterisk-the-definitive-guide-first-draft-complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2011 01:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/01/12/asterisk-the-definitive-guide-first-draft-complete/</guid>
      <description>Today we marked the finishing of Asterisk: The Definitive Guide (3rd Edition) by sending the first draft off to the O&amp;rsquo;Reilly production team. We finished nearly on schedule (within a few days, which is remarkable considering we added 150 more pages than originally intentioned) and have our favourite copy editor Rachel Head (formerly Wheeler) who did the first edition of Asterisk: The Future of Telephony who we emphatically enjoyed working with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asterisk: The Definitive Guide -- Call For Reviewers!</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/01/06/asterisk-the-definitive-guide----call-for-reviewers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2011 15:22:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/01/06/asterisk-the-definitive-guide----call-for-reviewers/</guid>
      <description>Here is the text I posted to the asterisk-doc mailing list this morning. You can sign up for asterisk-doc at http://lists.digium.com and get involved! We&amp;rsquo;d love to make this the best book on Asterisk ever, and your input can make that true! Our goal is to build a book for, and by, the Asterisk community.
&amp;ldquo;_Hey all! _
_We&amp;rsquo;re getting VERY close to having the first draft of the next Asterisk book, Asterisk: The Definitive Guide ready to be sent off to production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update for Asterisk: The Definitive Guide (3rd Edition)</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/12/21/update-for-asterisk-the-definitive-guide-3rd-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2010 15:54:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/12/21/update-for-asterisk-the-definitive-guide-3rd-edition/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve done an update on my blog, but that&amp;rsquo;s just because we&amp;rsquo;ve been so busy at work on the next edition of the O&amp;rsquo;Reilly published Asterisk book! Asterisk: The Definitive Guide is the next update to the Asterisk: The Future Of Telephony books and is thus the 3rd edition. We&amp;rsquo;ve changed the name for two reasons: 1) This is pretty much a complete re-write of the book based on Asterisk 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
