<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shell on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</title>
    <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/tags/shell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shell on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 21:20:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.leifmadsen.com/tags/shell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring powerline to show working Git branch</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2015/09/09/configuring-powerline-to-show-working-git-branch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 21:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2015/09/09/configuring-powerline-to-show-working-git-branch/</guid>
      <description>So the documentation for Powerline kind of sucks. I followed this pretty good article on getting started with it. First thing I noticed however is that the if statement on the article doesn&rsquo;t work if you don&rsquo;t have powerline installed (which kind of defeats the purpose of having the if statement there at all). # if powerline is installed, then use it command -v powerline-daemon &amp;&gt;/dev/null if [ $? -eq 0 ]; then powerline-daemon -q POWERLINE_BASH_CONTINUATION=1 POWERLINE_BASH_SELECT=1 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: Read a value from a file, and say it back</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/07/17/howto-read-a-value-from-a-file-and-say-it-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2009 17:21:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/07/17/howto-read-a-value-from-a-file-and-say-it-back/</guid>
      <description>Preamble Today on the VoIP Users Conference we discussed my request for recipe ideas in order to start developing some additional documentation. Specifically, I&rsquo;m looking for problems that are simple, common problems that can be solved in the dialplan, and which are good examples of the dialplan language (markup, script, yadda yadda). One of the suggestions was something posted to the Asterisk mailing list which was pretty straight forward: to read in the contents of a file, where the file contained a number which was the current temperature.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
