<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</title>
    <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 13:01:21 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a virtual undercloud with TripleO Quickstart</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2016/12/28/create-a-virtual-undercloud-with-tripleo-quickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 13:01:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2016/12/28/create-a-virtual-undercloud-with-tripleo-quickstart/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how I&amp;rsquo;m currently using TripleO Quickstart to instantiate a virtual machine on a remote virtual machine host from my workstation. In follow up blog posts I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how to utilize the virtual machine to provision both virtual and baremetal overclouds from the virtual machine.
Topology The topology for our lab environment is shown in image 1-1.
 Image 1-1: TripleO Quickstart Physical Layout   We have a laptop acting as the workstation (where we&amp;rsquo;ll do our work from), a virtual host (with lots of memory to run virtual machines), and 3 small physical hosts (Atom based) which will simulate nodes for a baremetal deployment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating virtual machines in libvirt with virt-install</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2016/12/16/creating-virtual-machines-in-libvirt-with-virt-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 14:36:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2016/12/16/creating-virtual-machines-in-libvirt-with-virt-install/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to automate my virtual machine instantiation for a while now,
but I&amp;rsquo;ve always hated the idea of having to spin up multiple bits of
infrastruction to deal with PXE booting, web server to host a kickstart file,
etc. Luckily, I ran into some stuff today, and figured out how to automate
virtual machine instantitation without having to resort to anything outside of
localhost.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial Fedora libvirt Setup</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2016/12/16/initial-fedora-libvirt-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 10:30:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2016/12/16/initial-fedora-libvirt-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are always a few things I need to do to get libvirt working with a
non-root user on Fedora that I need to do, and typically results in some Google
researching. Here are some notes of what I recently did to get my libvirt setup
going on a new Fedora 25 installation and working with a non-root user.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create network bridge with nmcli for libvirt</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2016/12/01/create-network-bridge-with-nmcli-for-libvirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 14:51:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2016/12/01/create-network-bridge-with-nmcli-for-libvirt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In order to get libvirt working properly with bridged networking, we first need
to configure our local network to have network bridge slaved to our wired
ethernet adapter. I don&amp;rsquo;t have to set this up too often (as once I do, it just
sits there running happily). Here are some basic steps I did to get this going
locally.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TripleO: Using the fake_pxe driver with Ironic</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2016/11/11/tripleo-using-the-fake_pxe-driver-with-ironic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2016/11/11/tripleo-using-the-fake_pxe-driver-with-ironic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on testing things with TripleO and normally I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/openstack/tripleo-quickstart/&#34;&gt;TripleO
Quickstart&lt;/a&gt; to spin things up
in a virtual environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often when doing NFV work though, you need things that can&amp;rsquo;t be used in a
virtual environment (such as DPDK, SR-IOV, etc) so you need some baremetal
nodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my home lab environment though, I don&amp;rsquo;t have the luxury of IPMI, so I need
to make use of the &lt;code&gt;fake_pxe&lt;/code&gt; driver in Ironic, which allows for standard PXE
control, but requires you to deal with powering on and off the machines
manually. Let me show you how I make use of that.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TripleO: Consuming Composable Roles</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2016/10/03/tripleo-consuming-composable-roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 15:34:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2016/10/03/tripleo-consuming-composable-roles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So last week I started to look into learning the new &lt;a href=&#34;http://hardysteven.blogspot.ca/2016/08/tripleo-composable-services-101.html&#34;&gt;composable services and
roles&lt;/a&gt;
that was added to Newton. I previously learned a little bit about deploying
OpenStack clouds when I did training after joining Red Hat, but that was based
on Liberty, and a lot has changed in TripleO since that time.

The first thing was learning what composable services and roles are, and
generally what they are intended to solve. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to get into that
here, so I&amp;rsquo;d encourage you to go read some links first and then come back here.
Additionally, it&amp;rsquo;s assumed you know what a TripleO is :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Console Obsession</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2016/09/27/a-console-obsession/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 16:11:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2016/09/27/a-console-obsession/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten into running as many of my day-to-day applications in a
Linux console. Thought I&amp;rsquo;d briefly share the applications I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing
with.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rules For The Greater Goodness; A Product Development Guide</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2015/11/19/rules-for-the-greater-goodness-a-product-development-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 10:21:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2015/11/19/rules-for-the-greater-goodness-a-product-development-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This page documents and provides bullets about the way to approach (or avoid)
building products. These are lessons we&amp;rsquo;ve learned from previous encounters and
which we wish to avoid in the future. By sticking firmly to these development
rules, we avoid getting bogged down in complete system rearchitectures in the
future. The means to a scaled end is to approach the first customer as all your
customers.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asterisk Docker Container: Phase 1</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2015/11/10/asterisk-docker-container-phase-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 19:41:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2015/11/10/asterisk-docker-container-phase-1/</guid>
      <description>AstriCon At AstriCon 2015 this year, there was a lot (and I mean a lot) of discussion around microservices (Docker), and what effort is required over the next year by the development community in order to make Asterisk better suited to running in that environment.
One of the first things is, clearly, to have a container image that Asterisk runs in. I&amp;rsquo;ve done this a few times now, but having something that can be passed over to the official Asterisk Git repository, and which everyone can contribute to, utilize and play with would be the goal here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 19:28:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I currently work at Red Hat on the NFV (Network Functions Virtualization) partner engineering team as the DevOps lead. In his role he works with telecommunication partners to automate and test their NFV platforms.
In a previous life, I was an Asterisk consultant, starting professionally in 2004 (learning Asterisk in September 2002). I&amp;rsquo;m co-author of the O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Media published books, Asterisk: The Future of Telephony 1st and 2nd editions (along with Jared Smith and Jim van Meggelen), Asterisk: The Definitive Guide (3rd edition) with Jim van Meggelen and Russell Bryant, and the Asterisk Cookbook with Russell Bryant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker container results in x509: failed to load system roots and no roots provided</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2015/10/30/docker-container-results-in-x509-failed-to-load-system-roots-and-no-roots-provided/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 20:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2015/10/30/docker-container-results-in-x509-failed-to-load-system-roots-and-no-roots-provided/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have a small system running in AWS as a CentOS 7 image. It has a few
containers that we&amp;rsquo;re using to host a few Golang API proxies. We migrated a
customers API proxy that was running on the local VM into a container, and spun
it up. Upon testing, we ran into the following error:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;x509: failed to load system roots and no roots provided
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring powerline to show working Git branch</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2015/09/09/configuring-powerline-to-show-working-git-branch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 21:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2015/09/09/configuring-powerline-to-show-working-git-branch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So the documentation for
&lt;a href=&#34;http://powerline.readthedocs.org/en/latest/index.html&#34;&gt;Powerline&lt;/a&gt; kind of
sucks. I followed
&lt;a href=&#34;http://fedoramagazine.org/add-power-terminal-powerline&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; pretty good
article on getting started with it. First thing I noticed however is that the
&lt;code&gt;if&lt;/code&gt; statement on the article doesn&amp;rsquo;t work if you don&amp;rsquo;t have powerline
installed (which kind of defeats the purpose of having the &lt;code&gt;if&lt;/code&gt; statement there
at all).
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rumors of my death have been greatly exaggerated</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2014/07/25/rumors-of-my-death-have-been-greatly-exaggerated/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 02:49:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2014/07/25/rumors-of-my-death-have-been-greatly-exaggerated/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been way too long since I&amp;rsquo;ve blogged. And this post isn&amp;rsquo;t going to be all the impressive unfortunately. However, I recently have been running a BBS and some friends and I have been playing LORD.
We&amp;rsquo;ve been playing this for the last few months, and I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to run a tournament. Perhaps with some sort of buy in like $10 or something, winner takes all.
Going to build it out in such a way that first person to beat the dragon 3 times will win the game, and at that point that person will win the pot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asterisk: The Definitive Guide 4th Edition goes to print</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2013/05/16/asterisk-the-definitive-guide-4th-edition-goes-to-print/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 13:31:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2013/05/16/asterisk-the-definitive-guide-4th-edition-goes-to-print/</guid>
      <description>Howdy folks,
Sorry for the lack of updates lately. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently (December 2012) started at Thinking Phone Networks as the Lead UC Systems Engineer, and we&amp;rsquo;ve been incredibly busy there. In addition, the authors and I had been working on the final touches to the 4th edition of Asterisk: The Definitive Guide, which documents Asterisk 11 LTS.
Late last week, the book went to print, and should start to appear on store shelves and start shipping from Amazon and other locations within the next 6-8 weeks I believe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brother printer doesn&#39;t print in Fedora 17</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2012/11/24/brother-printer-doesnt-print-in-fedora-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2012 22:06:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2012/11/24/brother-printer-doesnt-print-in-fedora-17/</guid>
      <description>Tip: If your Brother printer won&amp;rsquo;t print after installing the drivers, install glibc.i686
Today ran into an issue with my new Brother MFC-7460DN (which is a really nice laser printer with auto-feed scanner, Scan-to-FTP which creates a PDF file, and other things). I had just recently done a clean install of Fedora 17, and I could install the RPMs (which are i386 files on my x86_64 based system), add the printer to CUPS and all sorts of things that looked fine.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
