<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ofps on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</title>
    <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/tags/ofps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ofps on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 14:16:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.leifmadsen.com/tags/ofps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging the Asterisk Dialplan with Verbose()</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/03/04/debugging-the-asterisk-dialplan-with-verbose/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 14:16:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/03/04/debugging-the-asterisk-dialplan-with-verbose/</guid>
      <description>In case you missed it, Russell Bryant wrote a blog post on debugging the Asterisk dialplan with the Verbose() application. This is one of the recipes that will be features in the upcoming Asterisk Cookbook that we&amp;rsquo;re writing, and hoping to have done by the end of March! (In case you&amp;rsquo;ve missed all the cool stuff lately, the Asterisk Cookbook will also be released under the same Creative Commons license as the previous Asterisk books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asterisk Cookbook Is On! (We Think :))</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/01/27/asterisk-cookbook-is-on-we-think-/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2011 14:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/01/27/asterisk-cookbook-is-on-we-think-/</guid>
      <description>After finishing the first draft of Asterisk: The Definitive Guide (3rd Edition), I&amp;rsquo;ve been a bit antsy with wanting to do some more writing. After about a week of a break (i.e. sleeping in past 7am for the first time in nearly a year), Russell Bryant and I have decided to team up on delivering the long awaited Asterisk Cookbook. To start off with, we&amp;rsquo;ll be writing a short, 80-100 page eBook that will be distributed by O&amp;rsquo;Reilly in all the formats they support (http://oreilly.com/ebooks/).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asterisk: The Definitive Guide, First Draft Complete!</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/01/12/asterisk-the-definitive-guide-first-draft-complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2011 01:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/01/12/asterisk-the-definitive-guide-first-draft-complete/</guid>
      <description>Today we marked the finishing of Asterisk: The Definitive Guide (3rd Edition) by sending the first draft off to the O&amp;rsquo;Reilly production team. We finished nearly on schedule (within a few days, which is remarkable considering we added 150 more pages than originally intentioned) and have our favourite copy editor Rachel Head (formerly Wheeler) who did the first edition of Asterisk: The Future of Telephony who we emphatically enjoyed working with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update for Asterisk: The Definitive Guide (3rd Edition)</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/12/21/update-for-asterisk-the-definitive-guide-3rd-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2010 15:54:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/12/21/update-for-asterisk-the-definitive-guide-3rd-edition/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve done an update on my blog, but that&amp;rsquo;s just because we&amp;rsquo;ve been so busy at work on the next edition of the O&amp;rsquo;Reilly published Asterisk book! Asterisk: The Definitive Guide is the next update to the Asterisk: The Future Of Telephony books and is thus the 3rd edition. We&amp;rsquo;ve changed the name for two reasons: 1) This is pretty much a complete re-write of the book based on Asterisk 1.8 and 2) Asterisk is no longer the FUTURE of telephony; it&amp;rsquo;s the present.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
