<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Speaking on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</title>
    <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/tags/speaking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Speaking on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 12:08:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.leifmadsen.com/tags/speaking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>AstriCon 2010 and my talks!</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/10/27/astricon-2010-and-my-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 12:08:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/10/27/astricon-2010-and-my-talks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE: My presentations are available on my website at &lt;a href=&#34;http://leifmadsen.com&#34;&gt;http://leifmadsen.com&lt;/a&gt; under the Presentations tab.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey all! I&amp;rsquo;m at AstriCon 2010 in Maryland and it&amp;rsquo;s going great so far! Russell Bryant and I spoke with several keen users and developers last night in the Code Zone at a fairly late hour, which shows just how dedicated Asterisk users are. There was pretty much no one else around and we had a room of about 20-30 people just having a great discussion about Asterisk development. Hopefully more of that over the next few days!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today is the big keynote by some of the software development team, and while I can&amp;rsquo;t tell you what is going to be said, I can promise you it&amp;rsquo;s going to be big news. A lot of work has been going on over the last few months which has resulted in the biggest announcement yet at AstriCon about the future of telephony. There will be lots of blinky lights as well, which is always cool in a keynote!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond the keynote this morning will be a lot of very high quality talks. I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet planned out my list of talks that I&amp;rsquo;m going to see, but you should definitely mark my two talks on your list of things to see :) I&amp;rsquo;ll be speaking at 1:45pm today, October 27th in the Asterisk Essentials track with my updated &amp;ldquo;5 Things You Didn&amp;rsquo;t Know Asterisk Could Do&amp;rdquo; presentation. It&amp;rsquo;ll be in National Harbor #5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow on October 28th I&amp;rsquo;ll be filling in for Jim van Meggelen at 10:00am doing my &amp;ldquo;Building A Distributed Queue System&amp;rdquo; talk which will focus on the basics of Asterisk system design starting from a traditional PBX and taking it through the iterations of a distributed system with multiple physical boxes handling queues and phones distributed across multiple sites and locations. For those who missed it last year come check it out this year, and get there early because each time I do this talk the room is packed. It&amp;rsquo;s part of the Platform Solutions track which is in National Harbor #7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you around at AstriCon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: I&amp;rsquo;m trying to reach my 500th follower during AstriCon, so you should follow me on twitter :)  (@leifmadsen)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at AstriCon 2010! Come see my talk! :)</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/08/03/speaking-at-astricon-2010-come-see-my-talk-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 19:12:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/08/03/speaking-at-astricon-2010-come-see-my-talk-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorry for the lack of updates recently. We&amp;rsquo;ve been hard at work on the next version of the Asterisk book, which is shaping up to be the best book ever written on Asterisk. The scope and detail we&amp;rsquo;re working towards is ambitious, but will be very much worth it. Of course the book will be focused on the upcoming Asterisk 1.8 releases (which was recently &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.russellbryant.net/blog/2010/07/23/asterisk-1-8-0-beta1-now-available/&#34;&gt;branched&lt;/a&gt; and betas are now available for testing!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My talk this year at AstriCon will be &amp;ldquo;5 Things You Didn&amp;rsquo;t Know Asterisk Could Do&amp;rdquo; which is really an update on various new features in Asterisk 1.8 which you may or may not be aware of. Where possible (time permitting) I&amp;rsquo;ll be showing configuration setups for the options, or at least give you the overview of the features, what it can and can not do, along with links to some documentation. If I get really ambitious I might create blog posts covering all the features that I can then point back to after the talk!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, it looks like I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking at 1:45pm on October 27th, 2010 (which appears to be immediately after lunch&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ll have to be peppy to wake people up from their food comas!). The Agenda-at-a-Glance has been updated, and you can see me on the 27th:  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.astricon.net/agendaAtaGlance.aspx&#34;&gt;http://www.astricon.net/agendaAtaGlance.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.astricon.net&#34;&gt;AstriCon&lt;/a&gt; is always a great time with some very intelligent people, and I always learn something new each year. I&amp;rsquo;ve been to several different conferences, and this is probably one of the best balanced conferences in terms of sales vs. technical. If you&amp;rsquo;re into technical talks, but enjoy the polish that a conference with sales booths provides, you&amp;rsquo;re really going to enjoy AstriCon. I&amp;rsquo;ve been participating since 2004 and have never missed a conference. Can&amp;rsquo;t say that about any of the other conferences I&amp;rsquo;ve attended before.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking @ IT360, April 7th, 2010</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/03/17/speaking--it360-april-7th-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2010 15:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/03/17/speaking--it360-april-7th-2010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I will be speaking again at the IT360 conference in Toronto, ON, Canada in the Asterisk &amp;amp; Open Telephony portion of the conference. IT360 is on April 7 this year (2010) being held at the Metro Toronto Convention Centre. I will be speaking on the Super Panel – Enterprise Use, Security, Virtual Hosting, Mobility &amp;amp; More along with John Todd, Kevin Fleming, Steve Sokol, and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My primary focus will likely be on the large scale call centre implementations I&amp;rsquo;ve done, along with clustering, database integration, and distributed information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference starts at 8:30am and runs until the end of the super panel at 4:20pm. After that will be the TAUG (Toronto Asterisk Users Group) meeting where the guests of the super panel along with other speakers throughout the day will participate with anyone interested in attending. The TAUG meeting is free and open to all. If you would like to attend the conference, then you can use some of the information below that was posted on the TAUG mailing lists:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;To register use code ASC25 and you will receive a 25% discount on the
regular registration fee. So for early bird rate, the actual cost would
be $336.75 plus GST. This is a special rate for folks that are part of
TAUG:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://myprereg.com/Registration.aspx?show=98&amp;amp;website=52&amp;amp;Page=INTRO&#34;&gt;https://myprereg.com/Registration.aspx?show=98&amp;amp;website=52&amp;amp;Page=INTRO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To attend the marketplace only, TAUG members can use code TS1 for
complimentary admission and save $50 on the &amp;lsquo;at door&amp;rsquo; price.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, for independents and small businesses, an additional discount has been provided:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;For independents, and small businesses, IT360 has given us a code for 50%
off &amp;ndash; so for early bird registration, the total cost is $224.50 plus gst up
until March 19th. Then it becomes 50% off the advance price which makes it
$249.50. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested and feel your business qualifies, give the
TAUG number a call at 416-548-7557 to get the code.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope to see you at the conference and the TAUG meeting!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AstriCon 2010 officially announced; What should I submit for a talk proposal?!</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/02/23/astricon-2010-officially-announced-what-should-i-submit-for-a-talk-proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 14:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/02/23/astricon-2010-officially-announced-what-should-i-submit-for-a-talk-proposal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So AstriCon 2010 has been officially announced (although the information for where and when it was going to be held has been on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.astricon.net&#34;&gt;http://www.astricon.net&lt;/a&gt; site for a bit now &amp;ndash; perhaps contracts have been signed now?), and they are soliciting for speaker topics due for May 1st. I&amp;rsquo;ve either attended, spoken, or assisted with every AstriCon since 2004 (the first one!) and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to submitting another talk for this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digium.com/en/mediacenter/viewpress.php?id=Digium-Announces-Seventh-Annual-AstriCon-to-be-held-October-26-28-2010&#34;&gt;official AstriCon announcement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously I&amp;rsquo;ve generally spoken about technologies such as DUNDi, func_odbc, distributed Asterisk systems, and call centres. All of these topics have been well attended (and you can find links to previous talks at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.leifmadsen.com&#34;&gt;http://www.leifmadsen.com&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m asking for some ideas for talks that I could give. I generally dabble in the realm of database integration and call centres, but if there is a particular topic you&amp;rsquo;re looking for specifically I have enough time to research, lab up, and create several slides on probably nearly any topic in Asterisk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bring forth your ideas for AstriCon 2010 talks in the comments, and I hope to see you at my presentation!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>