<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Interview on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</title>
    <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/tags/interview/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Interview on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 21:30:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.leifmadsen.com/tags/interview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-term &#39;shopping list&#39; helps couple furnish Caledon townhouse</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/04/15/long-term-shopping-list-helps-couple-furnish-caledon-townhouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 21:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/04/15/long-term-shopping-list-helps-couple-furnish-caledon-townhouse/</guid>
      <description>Recently, @jenspeedy of http://www.yourhome.ca interviewed my fiancée and I about our recently purchased townhouse in Caledon after our designer @melissadavis of http://www.melissadavis.ca and http://www.designerfriend.ca recommended she speak to us. Danielle (my fiancée) and I had a pretty good idea about the items we wanted for our new townhouse build, but were looking for a designer to make sure we didn&amp;rsquo;t get too far off track, and to steer us into the direction we ultimately wanted to achieve, while not breaking the bank (i.e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview from Wind Mobile launch</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/02/09/interview-from-wind-mobile-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 22:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/02/09/interview-from-wind-mobile-launch/</guid>
      <description>I was interviewed at the Wind Mobile launch a couple of months ago, and was interviewed by an online publication. I didn&amp;rsquo;t remember which online publication it was, so had forgotten all about it until I noticed someone had posted a link to it in the on-asterisk mailing list. Enjoy! Wind Mobile launches with contract-free, unlimited plans Globalive&amp;rsquo;s Wind Mobile brand is officially live in Toronto and will soon be opening its doors in Calgary and other Canadian cities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jim van Meggelen, Open Source Telephony Renaissance Man</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/11/21/jim-van-meggelen-open-source-telephony-renaissance-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2009 15:04:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/11/21/jim-van-meggelen-open-source-telephony-renaissance-man/</guid>
      <description>In case you missed it, Suzanne Bowen of DIDX recently interviewed co-author of Asterisk: The Future of Telephony and good friend of mine, Jim van Meggelen. If you&amp;rsquo;ve never had a chance to see Jim speak at a conference, do yourself a favour and try to attend one of his sessions. He is extremely entertaining and informative, and is always a joy to speak to. Jim also talks about the much anticipated 3rd edition of Asterisk: The Future of Telephony.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
