<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pbx on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</title>
    <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/tags/pbx/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pbx on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/tags/pbx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating from AgentCallbackLogin() to Standard Dialplan Methods (part 1)</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/07/16/migrating-from-agentcallbacklogin-to-standard-dialplan-methods-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2009 02:59:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/07/16/migrating-from-agentcallbacklogin-to-standard-dialplan-methods-part-1/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this article is to ease the migration from AgentCallbackLogin() to using standard dialplan applications to solve the problem of calling back queue members (agents) who are logged into a queue.
We will look at some of the common uses of AgentCallbackLogin(), and explore how to perform the same functionality using the commonly available dialplan applications in Asterisk.
The version of Asterisk used in the following examples is based on a recent version of Asterisk 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leif Madsen @ IT360, April 2009</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/06/09/leif-madsen--it360-april-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 11:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/06/09/leif-madsen--it360-april-2009/</guid>
      <description>Here are the 5 parts of my presentation at IT360 in Toronto, ON, Canada in April 2009. The focus of my presentation were to pick 5 features of Asterisk that are either new, or have been in Asterisk for a while, but without much fan-fare. I hope you enjoy!
Leif Madsen @ IT360 (April 2009), Unusual Uses: What you didn&rsquo;t know your Asterisk system could do (parts 1-5)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the new Asterisk versioning method</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/06/06/about-the-new-asterisk-versioning-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2009 15:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/06/06/about-the-new-asterisk-versioning-method/</guid>
      <description>Recently I have been seeing more and more questions about how Asterisk is being released now, and what the 1.6.x versions really mean. I&rsquo;ll try and clear up some of your questions and make it more clear as to how Asterisk versions work. First, lets talk about the Asterisk 1.2 and 1.4 branches.
Previous release methodology When we just had Asterisk 1.2 and 1.4, all new development was carried out in trunk (it still is) and only bug fixes went into the 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
