<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Versioning on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</title>
    <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/tags/versioning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Versioning on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2011 20:27:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.leifmadsen.com/tags/versioning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Asterisk 10 == Asterisk 1.^H^H10</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/08/29/asterisk-10--asterisk-1.hh10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2011 20:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/08/29/asterisk-10--asterisk-1.hh10/</guid>
      <description>In case you missed it, the next version of Asterisk is now in beta, and at the same time, has undergone a minor version numbering scheme. As it is unlikely that Asterisk will ever have a 2.0 release since for years now, that has generally meant Asterisk would undergo a major underlying change in both how it was programmed and the user experience (and since it would be a major disruption to the Asterisk community), it was deemed unnecessary to utilize the 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the new Asterisk versioning method</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/06/06/about-the-new-asterisk-versioning-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2009 15:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/06/06/about-the-new-asterisk-versioning-method/</guid>
      <description>Recently I have been seeing more and more questions about how Asterisk is being released now, and what the 1.6.x versions really mean. I&amp;rsquo;ll try and clear up some of your questions and make it more clear as to how Asterisk versions work. First, lets talk about the Asterisk 1.2 and 1.4 branches. Previous release methodology When we just had Asterisk 1.2 and 1.4, all new development was carried out in trunk (it still is) and only bug fixes went into the 1.2 and 1.4 branches.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
