<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nfvpe on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</title>
    <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/categories/nfvpe/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nfvpe on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/categories/nfvpe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>TripleO: Using the fake_pxe driver with Ironic</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2016/11/11/tripleo-using-the-fake_pxe-driver-with-ironic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2016/11/11/tripleo-using-the-fake_pxe-driver-with-ironic/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on testing things with TripleO and normally I use TripleO Quickstart to spin things up in a virtual environment.
Often when doing NFV work though, you need things that can&amp;rsquo;t be used in a virtual environment (such as DPDK, SR-IOV, etc) so you need some baremetal nodes.
In my home lab environment though, I don&amp;rsquo;t have the luxury of IPMI, so I need to make use of the fake_pxe driver in Ironic, which allows for standard PXE control, but requires you to deal with powering on and off the machines manually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TripleO: Consuming Composable Roles</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2016/10/03/tripleo-consuming-composable-roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 15:34:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2016/10/03/tripleo-consuming-composable-roles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So last week I started to look into learning the new &lt;a href=&#34;http://hardysteven.blogspot.ca/2016/08/tripleo-composable-services-101.html&#34;&gt;composable services and
roles&lt;/a&gt;
that was added to Newton. I previously learned a little bit about deploying
OpenStack clouds when I did training after joining Red Hat, but that was based
on Liberty, and a lot has changed in TripleO since that time.

The first thing was learning what composable services and roles are, and
generally what they are intended to solve. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to get into that
here, so I&amp;rsquo;d encourage you to go read some links first and then come back here.
Additionally, it&amp;rsquo;s assumed you know what a TripleO is :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
