<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grub on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</title>
    <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/tags/grub/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Grub on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/tags/grub/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>CentOS 5.8 On AWS EC2 With Xen Kernel (PVGRUB)</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2012/08/22/centos-5.8-on-aws-ec2-with-xen-kernel-pvgrub/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 14:10:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2012/08/22/centos-5.8-on-aws-ec2-with-xen-kernel-pvgrub/</guid>
      <description>At CoreDial we&rsquo;ve been using a lot of AWS EC2 lately for building sandbox infrastructure for testing. Part of the infrastructure is a voice platform utilizing Asterisk 1.4 and 1.8, and those voice platforms are using Zaptel and DAHDI respectively for use with MeetMe(). This hasn&rsquo;t been an issue previously as our testing has either been on bare metal, or in other virtual machine systems where installation of a base image and standard kernel are not an issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial impressions of qemu-kvm (virtualization server)</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/02/09/initial-impressions-of-qemu-kvm-virtualization-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 01:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/02/09/initial-impressions-of-qemu-kvm-virtualization-server/</guid>
      <description>The qemu-kvm (http://www.linux-kvm.org/page/Main_Page) package on Ubuntu 10.10 allows you to create virtual machines much like VMware, Xen, etc.
My initial impressions are generally pretty positive. I like that it lets you install multiple operating systems (including MS Windows, which I haven&rsquo;t tried yet), and doesn&rsquo;t use a web interface like VMware Server 2 (which I&rsquo;ve found to be terribly crash prone, requiring a restart of the web interface at the least, and sometime the entire server needs to be restarted, often abruptly with the kill application).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
