<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vm on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</title>
    <link>http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/tags/vm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vm on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 01:18:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/tags/vm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial impressions of qemu-kvm (virtualization server)</title>
      <link>http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/blog/2011/02/09/initial-impressions-of-qemu-kvm-virtualization-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 01:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/blog/2011/02/09/initial-impressions-of-qemu-kvm-virtualization-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The qemu-kvm (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linux-kvm.org/page/Main_Page&#34;&gt;http://www.linux-kvm.org/page/Main_Page&lt;/a&gt;) package on Ubuntu 10.10 allows you to create virtual machines much like VMware, Xen, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My initial impressions are generally pretty positive. I like that it lets you install multiple operating systems (including MS Windows, which I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried yet), and doesn&amp;rsquo;t use a web interface like VMware Server 2 (which I&amp;rsquo;ve found to be terribly crash prone, requiring a restart of the web interface at the least, and sometime the entire server needs to be restarted, often abruptly with the kill application). My favourite part is the libvirt-manager that lets you manage the system and install virtual machines remotely over SSH using VNC (or at least something similar to it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one problem I had initially was installing CentOS 5.5. It was terribly slow, and when I started the virtual machine, I coudn&amp;rsquo;t get it past GRUB. I thought perhaps it was just a problem with running CentOS VMs on an Ubuntu host machine, but then I had the same problem with an Ubuntu installation (which took at least 3-4 times as long to install as CentOS for some reason).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got looking around and found people with similar issues as me, but they all basically just outlined reinstalling GRUB via a rescue disk. I tried this which got me just a little bit further, but still no GRUB menu, or system booting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I found a post indicating that restarting the KVM service caused things to work, which I tried doing, but nothing changed. So as a last ditch effort I tried rebooting the service, which I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to actually fix anything, but oddly enough worked. The existing VMs I installed started up fine, and the new installation I tried went significantly faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t had much of a chance to try more than what I&amp;rsquo;ve described, but thus far I like KVM a lot more than VMware. Hopefully I keep enjoying it as I go forward now that I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten VMs to boot :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>