<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Howto on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</title>
    <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/tags/howto/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Howto on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/tags/howto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Dialplan Functions: AES_DECRYPT() and AES_ENCRYPT()</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/09/09/using-dialplan-functions-aes_decrypt-and-aes_encrypt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 13:28:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/09/09/using-dialplan-functions-aes_decrypt-and-aes_encrypt/</guid>
      <description>I recently asked on twitter how many people would be interested in a set of blog posts that focused on how to use the various dialplan functions in Asterisk, and I got quite a positive response. I posted that shortly before getting married, and now that I&rsquo;m back into the groove of things, I&rsquo;m going to take a shot at posting a bunch of content focused around Asterisk dialplan functions. If you don&rsquo;t know what Asterisk dialplan functions are, head on over to the online version of Asterisk: The Definitive Guide (3rd edition) (or buy it) and read the section on dialplan functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scheduling automated calls between two participants with res_calendar</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/09/29/scheduling-automated-calls-between-two-participants-with-res_calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2010 14:25:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/09/29/scheduling-automated-calls-between-two-participants-with-res_calendar/</guid>
      <description>Here is a little dialplan snippet I wrote this morning for the next edition of the Asterisk book. While I&rsquo;m not going to delve into all the aspects of setting up res_calendar like we do in the book, I thought for those of you who might already have this working might enjoy it.
(The calendaring modules are available in Asterisk 1.8, which is currently in release candidate status. Check out http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asterisk IMAP and Gmail</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/09/20/asterisk-imap-and-gmail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2010 15:37:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/09/20/asterisk-imap-and-gmail/</guid>
      <description>Today I was working on the next edition of the Asterisk book and wanted to see if I could get Asterisk IMAP voicemail support to work with Gmail. I had tried doing this a few times in the past without success, but since I had spent some time documenting and testing against Dovecot last week for another client and gotten everything working, I figured I had a good base to start trying to connect to the Gmail IMAP servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing the Asterisk Test Suite</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/05/03/installing-the-asterisk-test-suite/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2010 15:17:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/05/03/installing-the-asterisk-test-suite/</guid>
      <description>In case you missed it, I wrote an introductory article about the Asterisk Test Suite on the Asterisk blog. The post takes you from a minimally installed Ubuntu 9.10 up to the point that you can run the tests in the test suite by going through all the possible errors you might encounter getting it loaded, and how to resolve those errors (most of them being missing dependencies).
Enjoy!
http://blogs.asterisk.org/2010/04/29/installing-the-asterisk-test-suite/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using a Nokia E71 with Asterisk (3G or WiFi)</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/03/19/using-a-nokia-e71-with-asterisk-3g-or-wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2010 16:28:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/03/19/using-a-nokia-e71-with-asterisk-3g-or-wifi/</guid>
      <description>There was some talk in one of the IRC chat rooms today about someone trying to get their E61i working with Asterisk. I haven&rsquo;t had an issue getting that phone or my E71 phone working, but regardless he was having issues. I figured I might as well spend a little bit of time today going through my configuration, both for my own reference, and so that other people can get their Nokia&rsquo;s setup with Asterisk as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Queues with Asterisk</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/11/14/building-queues-with-asterisk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2009 15:07:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/11/14/building-queues-with-asterisk/</guid>
      <description>Wow it&rsquo;s been a long time since I&rsquo;ve update my blog. Well, lets do that! :)
I&rsquo;ve just posted some documentation to the Asterisk issue tracker for review. It&rsquo;s about building queues with Asterisk. It is the start of probably 2 or 3 sets of documentation on building queues with Asterisk that I&rsquo;ll be submitting. You can find the documentation here for now:
https://issues.asterisk.org/view.php?id=16237
This documentation will likely be merged into core Asterisk at some point in the near future (doc/ subdirectory of your Asterisk source) and likely posted on http://blogs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: Getting Jabber/XMPP notifications from your PBX</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/07/18/howto-getting-jabber/xmpp-notifications-from-your-pbx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2009 03:47:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/07/18/howto-getting-jabber/xmpp-notifications-from-your-pbx/</guid>
      <description>I just have to write up a quick post to show you JUST HOW SIMPLE it is to get interesting events from your PBX via Jabber. Right now I&rsquo;m using it to notify me of anyone trying out my test ISN number, or whenever they join my conference bridge (good reminder if I lose track of time and forget that I scheduled some people to join my conference room).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: Read a value from a file, and say it back</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/07/17/howto-read-a-value-from-a-file-and-say-it-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2009 17:21:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/07/17/howto-read-a-value-from-a-file-and-say-it-back/</guid>
      <description>Preamble Today on the VoIP Users Conference we discussed my request for recipe ideas in order to start developing some additional documentation. Specifically, I&rsquo;m looking for problems that are simple, common problems that can be solved in the dialplan, and which are good examples of the dialplan language (markup, script, yadda yadda).
One of the suggestions was something posted to the Asterisk mailing list which was pretty straight forward: to read in the contents of a file, where the file contained a number which was the current temperature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: Page() all users, other than current channel</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/07/15/howto-page-all-users-other-than-current-channel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2009 18:29:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/07/15/howto-page-all-users-other-than-current-channel/</guid>
      <description>I was asked on IRC by bhodder how to Page() all users, other than the current channel (i.e. he had a list of people to call, but one of the channels listed could be the person paging, and he didn&rsquo;t want them paged).
So I wrote up the following little dialplan script which takes the list of users, and compares it against the current channel, and simply rebuilds the list without the current channel in it prior to calling the Page() application.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
