<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>It360 on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</title>
    <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/tags/it360/</link>
    <description>Recent content in It360 on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2010 15:27:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.leifmadsen.com/tags/it360/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking @ IT360, April 7th, 2010</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/03/17/speaking--it360-april-7th-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2010 15:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/03/17/speaking--it360-april-7th-2010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I will be speaking again at the IT360 conference in Toronto, ON, Canada in the Asterisk &amp;amp; Open Telephony portion of the conference. IT360 is on April 7 this year (2010) being held at the Metro Toronto Convention Centre. I will be speaking on the Super Panel – Enterprise Use, Security, Virtual Hosting, Mobility &amp;amp; More along with John Todd, Kevin Fleming, Steve Sokol, and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My primary focus will likely be on the large scale call centre implementations I&amp;rsquo;ve done, along with clustering, database integration, and distributed information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference starts at 8:30am and runs until the end of the super panel at 4:20pm. After that will be the TAUG (Toronto Asterisk Users Group) meeting where the guests of the super panel along with other speakers throughout the day will participate with anyone interested in attending. The TAUG meeting is free and open to all. If you would like to attend the conference, then you can use some of the information below that was posted on the TAUG mailing lists:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;To register use code ASC25 and you will receive a 25% discount on the
regular registration fee. So for early bird rate, the actual cost would
be $336.75 plus GST. This is a special rate for folks that are part of
TAUG:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://myprereg.com/Registration.aspx?show=98&amp;amp;website=52&amp;amp;Page=INTRO&#34;&gt;https://myprereg.com/Registration.aspx?show=98&amp;amp;website=52&amp;amp;Page=INTRO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To attend the marketplace only, TAUG members can use code TS1 for
complimentary admission and save $50 on the &amp;lsquo;at door&amp;rsquo; price.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, for independents and small businesses, an additional discount has been provided:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;For independents, and small businesses, IT360 has given us a code for 50%
off &amp;ndash; so for early bird registration, the total cost is $224.50 plus gst up
until March 19th. Then it becomes 50% off the advance price which makes it
$249.50. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested and feel your business qualifies, give the
TAUG number a call at 416-548-7557 to get the code.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope to see you at the conference and the TAUG meeting!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>