<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Asterisk Book on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</title>
    <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/tags/asterisk-book/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Asterisk Book on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/tags/asterisk-book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Asterisk: The Definitive Guide -- Call For Reviewers!</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/01/06/asterisk-the-definitive-guide----call-for-reviewers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2011 15:22:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/01/06/asterisk-the-definitive-guide----call-for-reviewers/</guid>
      <description>Here is the text I posted to the asterisk-doc mailing list this morning. You can sign up for asterisk-doc at http://lists.digium.com and get involved! We&amp;rsquo;d love to make this the best book on Asterisk ever, and your input can make that true! Our goal is to build a book for, and by, the Asterisk community.
&amp;ldquo;_Hey all! _
_We&amp;rsquo;re getting VERY close to having the first draft of the next Asterisk book, Asterisk: The Definitive Guide ready to be sent off to production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on TFoT v3 Progress</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/02/19/update-on-tfot-v3-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 14:39:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/02/19/update-on-tfot-v3-progress/</guid>
      <description>Just another quick update on the progress of the 3rd edition of the Asterisk book. It&amp;rsquo;s been a bit slow coming, but Jim and I have renewed vigor and vigilance to be productive and get things done. Since the last update, there was a period of time where nothing got done unfortunately. We did get a lot done in the week off I took to focus on the book (I think we ended up writing about 2-3 new chapters, and updated a lot of the old ones), but then of course work got in the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New articles coming soon!</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/06/17/new-articles-coming-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 01:24:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/06/17/new-articles-coming-soon/</guid>
      <description>I have vowed to try and write at least ONE article per week on my blog, even if it is quite short. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I will be able to get to write an article this week due to some pressing consulting issues, but I&amp;rsquo;m still gonna try. If anything, I&amp;rsquo;m going to cheat and say this is my post for this week. How about I make a rule that says I can only cheat once per month?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
