<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Https on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</title>
    <link>http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/tags/https/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Https on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 20:30:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/tags/https/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker container results in x509: failed to load system roots and no roots provided</title>
      <link>http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/blog/2015/10/30/docker-container-results-in-x509-failed-to-load-system-roots-and-no-roots-provided/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 20:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/blog/2015/10/30/docker-container-results-in-x509-failed-to-load-system-roots-and-no-roots-provided/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have a small system running in AWS as a CentOS 7 image. It has a few containers that we&amp;rsquo;re using to host a few Golang API proxies. We migrated a customers API proxy that was running on the local VM into a container, and spun it up. Upon testing, we ran into the following error:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;x509: failed to load system roots and no roots provided
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We get that failure when trying to connect to an HTTPS endpoint (remote API that we&amp;rsquo;re proxying to Asterisk).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figured it had to do with the fact we were using a scratch disk to build the container image, and that there were no certs loaded. Did some Googling and found some people with similar problems, but their solutions didn&amp;rsquo;t work for us on our CentOS 7 host system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I thought maybe there was some issue with following a symlink as the source since we were loading in the &lt;code&gt;ca-bundle.crt&lt;/code&gt; file as a volume. I didn&amp;rsquo;t test enough to determine if that was the issue (it probably wasn&amp;rsquo;t), but this post gave me a hint:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/docker/issues/5157#issuecomment-69325677&#34;&gt;https://github.com/docker/docker/issues/5157#issuecomment-69325677&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we did the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker run -d -p 8085:8085 -v /etc/pki/ca-trust/extracted/pem/tls-ca-bundle.pem:/etc/ssl/certs/ca-certificates.crt [etc...]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After linking that file and mounting it in the container, all was well. I suspect it&amp;rsquo;s the path to the &lt;code&gt;ca-certificates.crt&lt;/code&gt; that was the real trick.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>