<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Openstack on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</title>
    <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/categories/openstack/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Openstack on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/categories/openstack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a virtual undercloud with TripleO Quickstart</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2016/12/28/create-a-virtual-undercloud-with-tripleo-quickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 13:01:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2016/12/28/create-a-virtual-undercloud-with-tripleo-quickstart/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how I&amp;rsquo;m currently using TripleO Quickstart to instantiate a virtual machine on a remote virtual machine host from my workstation. In follow up blog posts I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how to utilize the virtual machine to provision both virtual and baremetal overclouds from the virtual machine.
Topology The topology for our lab environment is shown in image 1-1.
 Image 1-1: TripleO Quickstart Physical Layout   We have a laptop acting as the workstation (where we&amp;rsquo;ll do our work from), a virtual host (with lots of memory to run virtual machines), and 3 small physical hosts (Atom based) which will simulate nodes for a baremetal deployment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TripleO: Consuming Composable Roles</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2016/10/03/tripleo-consuming-composable-roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 15:34:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2016/10/03/tripleo-consuming-composable-roles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So last week I started to look into learning the new &lt;a href=&#34;http://hardysteven.blogspot.ca/2016/08/tripleo-composable-services-101.html&#34;&gt;composable services and
roles&lt;/a&gt;
that was added to Newton. I previously learned a little bit about deploying
OpenStack clouds when I did training after joining Red Hat, but that was based
on Liberty, and a lot has changed in TripleO since that time.

The first thing was learning what composable services and roles are, and
generally what they are intended to solve. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to get into that
here, so I&amp;rsquo;d encourage you to go read some links first and then come back here.
Additionally, it&amp;rsquo;s assumed you know what a TripleO is :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
