<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</title>
    <link>http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 13:05:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Commodore 64 Turns 30 This Year</title>
      <link>http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/blog/2012/01/09/commodore-64-turns-30-this-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 13:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/blog/2012/01/09/commodore-64-turns-30-this-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having found an article about the Commodore 64 turning 30 this year, I reflected back in a comment on that page about what it is like to be only 1 year older than the Commodore 64, a computer which spiked my interest in technology away from a games system to something much more. The original article is available at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/commodor-64-30-year&#34;&gt;http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/commodor-64-30-year&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I just turned 31 a couple of days ago on January 7th, and when I was in grade 2 (about 8-9 years old I guess) I started getting interested in the Commodore 64s we had at our school that were plentiful, but rarely used. I remember the first thing the teacher taught me; $p$g&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Commodore 64 replaced my interest with Nintendo (which I still have) to a greater interest that shaped me and caused me to grow technologically.  This grew into the Packard Bell &lt;sup&gt;486&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;25&lt;/sub&gt; my parents bought where I played flight simulator (after my Dad purchased more RAM for the computer at $100 a MB), and ran a BBS (the first month I played around with the 2400 baud modem calling Las Vegas BBS numbers that a friends father gave me; I lived in Sarnia, ON, Canada which is north-east of Detroit), and eventually ran my own BBS. Running a BBS gave me the sense of community that I possess and the love of telecommunications that is my career to this day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So thank you Commodore for your C64 which has allowed me to carve out my career and greatly influenced who I am; and not just professionally.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why NDAs are Useless</title>
      <link>http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/blog/2009/12/09/why-ndas-are-useless/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2009 23:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/blog/2009/12/09/why-ndas-are-useless/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a post I came across from my twitter feed discussing why NDAs are essentially useless and unenforceable in the digital age. Many good points are made, and for the most part I agree with them. I&amp;rsquo;m not quite so vehemently opposed to them as the author is as I know they aren&amp;rsquo;t enforceable. The reason I sign them is a good faith gesture to my clients. I think we both know they aren&amp;rsquo;t useful, but it gives the client a nice litmus test to determine whether I&amp;rsquo;m just looking to steal ideas, or at least to say, &amp;ldquo;Hey, it&amp;rsquo;d be great if you didn&amp;rsquo;t twitter or blog about anything you learn while looking at our system.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; at least not directly of course, you can&amp;rsquo;t ask me to forget something I may have learned while working on a project for you :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.contrast.ie/blog/five-reasons-to-drop-ndas/&#34;&gt;http://www.contrast.ie/blog/five-reasons-to-drop-ndas/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>