<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Infrastructure on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</title>
    <link>http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/tags/infrastructure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Infrastructure on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 20:22:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/tags/infrastructure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Now working with CoreDial</title>
      <link>http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/blog/2012/01/04/now-working-with-coredial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 20:22:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leifmadsen.github.io/hugo_gh_blog/blog/2012/01/04/now-working-with-coredial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://si0.twimg.com/profile_images/1509716558/twitter-coredial-square-avatar_reasonably_small.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt; As of January 3rd, I&amp;rsquo;m now working with the CoreDial team full time. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with them as a consultant on their infrastructure over the last few years but now will be spending significantly more time working with the engineering team :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the announcement,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“_CoreDial is pleased to announce the addition of Leif Madsen to the CoreDial team,” said Alan Rihm, CEO at CoreDial. “Leif is a well known Asterisk consultant who specializes in distributed telephony deployments and database integration. In addition, Leif is co-author of several O’Reilly published books on Asterisk, including Asterisk: The Definitive Guide (3rd edition). We’re pleased to be adding Leif to our team, and look forward to the exciting opportunity to work together._”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire announcement can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;http://coredial.com/asterisk-consultant-leif-madsen-joins-coredial-team/&#34;&gt;http://coredial.com/asterisk-consultant-leif-madsen-joins-coredial-team/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to be working with these guys, and to see what we&amp;rsquo;ll develop over the coming months! I&amp;rsquo;ll keep you informed here on my blog, and will continue to post Asterisk tidbits and snippets as I go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>