<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tfot on Leif Madsen.</title>
    <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/tags/tfot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tfot on Leif Madsen.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Leif Madsen</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 14:39:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/tfot/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on TFoT v3 Progress</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/02/19/update-on-tfot-v3-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 14:39:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/02/19/update-on-tfot-v3-progress/</guid>
      <description>Just another quick update on the progress of the 3rd edition of the Asterisk book. It&amp;rsquo;s been a bit slow coming, but Jim and I have renewed vigor and vigilance to be productive and get things done. Since the last update, there was a period of time where nothing got done unfortunately. We did get a lot done in the week off I took to focus on the book (I think we ended up writing about 2-3 new chapters, and updated a lot of the old ones), but then of course work got in the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: Asterisk TFoT v3 Progressing Nicely</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/11/27/update-asterisk-tfot-v3-progressing-nicely/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2009 13:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/11/27/update-asterisk-tfot-v3-progressing-nicely/</guid>
      <description>Jim and I have been working feverishly for the past few days, and the only thing that can cure it is more cowbell! Or probably more accurately, more writing!
We&amp;rsquo;ve been making some good progress on rewriting a couple of chapters so far, and tweaking a few other ones. We&amp;rsquo;re in the process of finishing up the first drafts of the new installation chapter and the initial configuration chapter, and I&amp;rsquo;ve started work on a chapter about queues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting work on Asterisk: TFoT 3rd edition</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/11/23/starting-work-on-asterisk-tfot-3rd-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2009 14:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/11/23/starting-work-on-asterisk-tfot-3rd-edition/</guid>
      <description>As many of you know, I&amp;rsquo;m a co-author of Asterisk: The Future of Telephony. While my girlfriend is away in Mexico for a week with the girls, I&amp;rsquo;m going to try and focus a bunch of attention on getting A:TFoT 3rd edition started (which is much overdue).
If you have any ideas for topics you would like covered in the new edition, or something that wasn&amp;rsquo;t covered as heavily as you wanted in the 1st and 2nd editions, feel free to let me know, and your ideas will be considered!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New articles coming soon!</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/06/17/new-articles-coming-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 01:24:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/06/17/new-articles-coming-soon/</guid>
      <description>I have vowed to try and write at least ONE article per week on my blog, even if it is quite short. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I will be able to get to write an article this week due to some pressing consulting issues, but I&amp;rsquo;m still gonna try. If anything, I&amp;rsquo;m going to cheat and say this is my post for this week. How about I make a rule that says I can only cheat once per month?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
