<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Queues on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</title>
    <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/tags/queues/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Queues on Asterisk, and other worldly endeavours</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2011 15:31:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.leifmadsen.com/tags/queues/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Asterisk Powered Distributed Call Centres (Video)</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/12/23/asterisk-powered-distributed-call-centres-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2011 15:31:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/12/23/asterisk-powered-distributed-call-centres-video/</guid>
      <description>Looks like TMC has posted my presentation from AstriCon 2011! You can see the presentation in its entirety over here: http://www.tmcnet.com/tmc/videos/default.aspx?vid=5821&amp;amp;title=Asterisk-Powered+Distributed+Call+Centers And the presentation along with the demo configuration files is available on my website at: http://leifmadsen.com/sites/default/files/AstriCon%202011%20-%20Building%20a%20distributed%20call%20centre.zip</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#AstriCon 2011: Building a Distributed Call Centre</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/10/26/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 19:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/10/26/</guid>
      <description>The presentation and configuration files from my presentation at AstriCon 2011 today is available at: http://leifmadsen.com/sites/default/files/AstriCon 2011 - Building a distributed call centre.zip</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AstriCon presentation today at 11:40am</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/10/26/astricon-presentation-today-at-1140am/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 16:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2011/10/26/astricon-presentation-today-at-1140am/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be speaking at AstriCon today (and tomorrow) about building a distributed call centre. The presentation will be 35 minutes long and will contain a set of slides that moves you from an existing traditional PBX system up through a distributed model (which happens to use a call centre as the example system). A PDF of the presentation along with the configuration files from the demo will be available on my website after the presentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Presentations from AstriCon 2010 are Available</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/11/01/my-presentations-from-astricon-2010-are-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2010/11/01/my-presentations-from-astricon-2010-are-available/</guid>
      <description>Check out http://leifmadsen.com and click on the presentations tab. Under that tab you will find my presentations from AstriCon 2010, &amp;rsquo;5 Things You Didn&amp;rsquo;t Know Asterisk Could Do&amp;rsquo; and a slightly updated version of my &amp;lsquo;Building Distributed Queue Systems&amp;rsquo; presentation. Both are in PDF format. Both presentations went over extremely well, and I think both probably ended up being, or nearly being, my best presentations ever given. In previous years I&amp;rsquo;ve given presentations on distributed Asterisk systems and last year at IT360 I gave my &amp;rdquo;5 Things You Didn&amp;rsquo;t Know Asterisk Could Do&amp;rdquo; presentation, so perhaps being somewhat familiar with the format helped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AstriCon 2009 Presentation -- Building a Distributed Call Center</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/11/18/astricon-2009-presentation----building-a-distributed-call-center/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 20:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/11/18/astricon-2009-presentation----building-a-distributed-call-center/</guid>
      <description>For those who missed it, you&amp;rsquo;re able to get a PDF of my AstriCon 2009 presentation from the http://www.astricon.net website. http://images.tmcnet.com/expo/astricon/presentations/cc01-madsen-digium.pdf There are additional presentations available from the conference as well. Check them out here: http://www.astricon.net/2009/astricon/agendaAtaGlance.aspx Overall, the conference was extremely well attended and I had a great time. I&amp;rsquo;ve been to a lot of conferences, and AstriCon is definitely a premiere conference that is professionally run, and contains a great deal of useful information by well versed presenters with little fluff (i.e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Queues with Asterisk</title>
      <link>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/11/14/building-queues-with-asterisk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2009 15:07:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.leifmadsen.com/blog/2009/11/14/building-queues-with-asterisk/</guid>
      <description>Wow it&amp;rsquo;s been a long time since I&amp;rsquo;ve update my blog. Well, lets do that! :) I&amp;rsquo;ve just posted some documentation to the Asterisk issue tracker for review. It&amp;rsquo;s about building queues with Asterisk. It is the start of probably 2 or 3 sets of documentation on building queues with Asterisk that I&amp;rsquo;ll be submitting. You can find the documentation here for now: https://issues.asterisk.org/view.php?id=16237 This documentation will likely be merged into core Asterisk at some point in the near future (doc/ subdirectory of your Asterisk source) and likely posted on http://blogs.asterisk.org as well.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
